randstad.com 2014-11-21

# privacy statement | Randstad.com

##  Privacy Statement Randstad Holding nv 

**Privacy Statement Randstad Holding nv**

**Introduction**

Randstad Holding nv (Chamber of Commerce registration number HR 33216172) is a public limited company based in the Netherlands and active in the HR services industry.

This policy explains what personal information Randstad Holding nv (referred in this policy as: we or Randstad Holding) collects about you on our website.

Randstad Holding is the data controller - as defined in the Dutch Data Protection Act (NL: _Wet Bescherming Persoonsgegevens, WBP_ ) in respect of any of the personal information we collect and process  through our website. To the extent required and in accordance with the WBP Randstad Holding has registered its data processing with the Dutch Data Protection Authority (College Bescherming Persoonsgegevens) in The Hague. These registrations are publicly available (see www.cbpweb.nl).

**Technical information**

In general you can visit Randstad.com without sharing any of your personal data with us. Like many other websites Randstad.com does collect automatically certain non-identifiable information on the users of the website, such as the Internet Protocol (IP)-address of your device, the IP-address of your Internet Service Provider, date and time of visit to the website, IP-address of the website which has directly linked you to our website, your operating system, the sections and pages you visit on our website and the information you viewed, as well as any information uploaded to or downloaded from the website. This technical information is used by the system administrator for the management/administration of our website, to analyze the use of our website and to make improvements. These technical details may be shared with third parties and may be retained for future use.

**Cookies**

Randstad Holding makes use of cookies and web analytics. We do so to monitor how visitors use our website. This information helps us to improve our website and to customize your personal user experience. Cookies are small text files placed on your device when you visit our website. During any next visit to our website these cookies can be recognized. Further information on this can be found in our cookies statement (<http://www.randstad.com/cookies>).

**How do we collect information from you and with whom do we share it**

In addition to the technical information and cookies we may collect further personal data from you. But we shall only do so when you decide to voluntarily share such personal data with us. We shall use your personal data in accordance with this privacy statement. If and how we use your personal data depends on your reason for visiting our website.

_General_

If you are visiting our website to find the link to a local website of any of our group entities, we do not collect personal data from you. When you click to link to another website, the privacy statement of that website shall be applicable.

If you provide us information via the contact form on our website we will collect your name and e-mail address as well as any other personal information you may provide yourself in the comment box. We will only use this data in relation to the reason for which you have contacted us.

_Candidates – jobs at Randstad_

If you are visiting our website because you are looking for a job through the global job search bar and decide to apply for any job posted, you are requested to provide your name, e-mail address, reasons for application and you may attach your resume. This data will not be processed by Randstad Holding; your personal data will be shared directly with the relevant Randstad Group company that posted the job vacancy. The privacy policy of that Randstad Group company will be applicable. If you apply for a job at Randstad Holding, your data will then remain with us for the sole purpose of assessing your suitability for the relevant job.

_Investors and anyone else visiting the “investor relations” section_

The “investor relations” section on Randstad.com allows you to subscribe to our alert service. You can indicate what alerts you want to receive. For this purpose you will have to share your basic contact details with us:

-      Your full name  
-      Your country  
-      Investor type  
-      E-mail address

We will only use this data to send you the alerts indicated by you. If at any time you wish to stop receiving the alerts, you can unsubscribe via the link in the newsletter. In that case we shall no longer retain your data.

_Clients and anyone else accessing the thought leadership hub “workforce360”_

In order to be able to access and download specific knowledge articles, publications, to receive newsletters etc. from workforce360 you will have to share your basic contact details with us:

-         Title (Sir/Madam)  
-         Your full name  
-         Your email address  
-         Your company name  
-         Your job title

We will use this data for limited marketing purposes related to our services, to send you newsletters and general analytics. We will share this data with our respective Randstad group companies based in your country who will also use this data for the same purposes and may contact you regarding Randstad’s services. When you register your data you explicitly agree to opt-in for these purposes.

If at any time you wish to stop receiving our e-mails, you can unsubscribe via the link in the newsletter. In that case we shall no longer retain your data.

**How long will Randstad Holding retain your data?**

When you have provided your details to us via the contact form on our website, we shall retain your data as long as it is necessary in relation to the reason for which you have contacted us or to provide any requested services to you. Your data shall be permanently anonymized ultimately one year after our final contact.

When you have provided your details either in the investor relations section or for workforce360, your data will remain with us as long as you want to receive the investor relations alerts and/or workforce 360 newsletters and related marketing communication from us. If at any time you wish to stop receiving our alerts and/or workforce360 newsletters and related marketing communication, you can indicate this in the email by clicking the “unsubscribe” button. Your data will either be deleted or permanently anonymized. We shall delete or permanently anonymize your data in any case ultimately after 2 years if there has been no contact between us during that period. If we receive a failure notice on sending you an alert, newsletter or email we shall also delete or permanently anonymize your data.   
Once permanently anonymized the data shall only be used for analytical purposes.

**How does Randstad secure your data**

We are committed to ensuring that the information you provided on our website is secure. We have therefore implemented appropriate technical and organizational measures to secure your personal data against loss and any form of unlawful processing. We have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure any data we collect form you on our website.

We shall never sell any personal data to any third party. We shall not give your personal data to third parties, unless we are under an obligation by law, for example in case of a lawful request by law enforcement authorities. We may, however, share your data with relevant Randstad group companies in relation to the activities stated above.

**Your rights with respect to your data**

You can file a request to access the data that is processed through [www.randstad.com](http://www.randstad.com/) by sending an email or letter to Corporate Communications (see below for details). Following your access request, you may review the information we hold about you and you may request us to rectify or remove your data in case the information is factually incorrect or was collected for a specific purpose, but the data is incomplete or not relevant for the purpose, or used in violation of the law. When you send us an access request, we may ask you to send us proof of who you are (e.g. a copy of your ID with your photograph and personal social security number blackened out). We will answer your request within four weeks.

**How to contact us if you have any questions**

If you have any questions about this policy or any privacy concerns, or wish to make an access request, please contact us by e-mail: [corporate.communications@randstadholding.com](mailto:corporate.communications@randstadholding.com), or send a letter to:

Randstad Holding nv  
attn. of Corporate Communications  
Diemermere 25  
1112 TC Diemen  
The Netherlands.

**Updates of this policy**

We may change our privacy practices and this policy. If we do we will post an updated version of this document on our website. It will have a different date and version number from the one set out below. You are advised to check our site periodically for updates.

Date: 26 May 2014

Version 1.0
